<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ad deliberationem gaolæ Domini Regis de Newgate tentam pro civitate London, apud Iustice-Hall in le Old Baily, in parochia Sancti Sepulchuri in warda de  Faringdon extra London, die Mercurii, scilicet decimo sexto de Aprilis, anno Regni Domini nostri Caroli, ... or, the better ordering, establishment and service of the watches, to be from henceforth duely observed and kept within the city of London and Liberties thereof, ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1645</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75857</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A462</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason 669.f.10[29]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R210380</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99869185</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99869185</idno>
            <idno type="VID">162570</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75857)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 162570)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 246:669f10[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Ad deliberationem gaolæ Domini Regis de Newgate tentam pro civitate London, apud Iustice-Hall in le Old Baily, in parochia Sancti Sepulchuri in warda de  Faringdon extra London, die Mercurii, scilicet decimo sexto de Aprilis, anno Regni Domini nostri Caroli, ... or, the better ordering, establishment and service of the watches, to be from henceforth duely observed and kept within the city of London and Liberties thereof, ...</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Richard Cotes, Printer to the Honourable City of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1645]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Text in English, black letter.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "16 Aprill 1645".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Police --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:162570:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the Old Bailey</figDesc>
               </figure> 
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the City of London</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>London ſſ.</hi> Ad deliberationem Gaolae Domini Regis de <hi>Newgate</hi> tentam pro Civitate <hi>London,</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pud Iuſtice-Hall in le <hi>Old Baily,</hi> in parochia Sancti <hi>Sepulchri</hi> in Warda de <hi>Faringdon</hi> extra <hi>London,</hi> 
                  <date>die Mercurii, ſcilicet decimo ſexto die Aprilis, Anno Regni Domini noſtri Caroli, dei gratia <hi>Angliae, Scotiae, Franciae,</hi> &amp; <hi>Hiberniae</hi> Regis, fidei defenſoris, &amp;c. viceſimo primo;</date>
               </dateline> Coram <hi>Thoma Atkin</hi> Majore Civitatis <hi>London, Nicholao Raynton</hi> milite, <hi>Iſaaco Pennington</hi> locum-tenen. Turris <hi>London</hi> uno Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermanorum dicte Civitatis, <hi>Iohanne Wollaſton</hi> milite, <hi>Iohanne Glynne</hi> Recordatore dicte Civitatis <hi>London, Iohanne Cordell</hi> milite, uno Aldermannorum dicte Civitatis <hi>London, Thoma Soame</hi> milite altero Aldermannorum dicte Civitatis <hi>London, Iohanne Gayer,</hi> milite altero Aldermannorum dicte Civita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tis <hi>London,</hi> &amp; aliis ſociis ſuis Iuſticiariis dicti domini Regis ad Gaolam ſuam de <hi>Newgate</hi> de priſoni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus in eadem exiſtentibus dliberand. aſſignatis.</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Or the better ordering, eſtabliſhment and ſervice of the Watches, to bee from henceforth duely obſerved and kept within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof: It is Ordered and declared by this Court as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">
               <hi>1.</hi> That the number of men to watch every night in every Ward throughout this City and liberties ſhall bee as hereafter is expreſſed, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Algate</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dukes place</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Alderſgate</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Martin le Grand</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Biſhopſgate</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Broadſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Billingſgate</cell>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Bridge within</cell>
                     <cell>25</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Baſſingſhaw</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Breadſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Cornehill</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Candlewicke</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Cordwayner</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Cheape</cell>
                     <cell>25</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Colemanſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>32</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Cripplegate within</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Cripplegate without</cell>
                     <cell>90</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Caſtle Baynard</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dowgate</cell>
                     <cell>36</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Farringdon within</cell>
                     <cell>50</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Muckwellſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Blackefryers</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Farringdon without</cell>
                     <cell>130</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>White fryers</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Bridewell Precinct</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Bartholomew the Great</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Bartholomew the Leſſe</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Limeſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Langborne</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Portſoken</cell>
                     <cell>60</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Queenehithe</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Towerſtreete</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Vintrey</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Walbrooke</cell>
                     <cell>20</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p n="2">
               <hi>2.</hi> That the Alderman, Deputy, and Common-Councell-men of every Ward, or the maior part of them, ſhall appoint a certain place within the Ward where the Inhabitants that are ſo appointed to watch ſhall firſt meet, and ſhall alſo appoint to what places they ſhall afterwards goe unto, to watch in the ſaid Ward, and that the Beadles, the day preceeding every watch, ſhall give to all the Conſtables of each Precinct in the Ward, a liſt of the names of every Inhabitant that is to watch each night in the ſeverall diviſions of the ſaid Ward, that every Conſtable may know what perſons hee is to warn to watch every ſeverall night, and that the Conſtable doe the day before his watch night warn them accordingly. And this Court doth declare, that every Watchman of any of the Wards aforeſaid, is to doe his ſervice in watching throughout the whole ward without limitation or confinement to any particular place or Precinct of that Ward. And the Inhabitants of every Ward are from henceforth to take notice hereof, and are Ordered and requeſted to do accordingly, notwithſtanding any pretence of priviledge to the contrary.</p>
            <p n="3">
               <hi>3.</hi> That the Watches ſhall be ſet, and continued for the times by the Law appointed.</p>
            <p n="4">
               <hi>4.</hi> That two, or more, honeſt able men ſhall be nominated in every Ward, by the Alderman, Deputy, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Councell men or the maior part of them for the time being, to take care, and overſee that the Watches appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted in every Ward, be from henceforth duely kept, and that the Conſtables, Beadle, and Watchmen, perform their duties, and therefore for that purpoſe a liſt ſhall be delivered unto the ſaid Superviſors in writing under the hands of the Alderman, Deputy, and Common-Councell-men of the names and Sirnames of the men ſo appointed to watch; and of the ſeverall places where they are aſſigned unto, to watch every night: Which ſaid Superviſor ſhall take notice of the ſaid Inhabitants that abſent themſelves at any time from watching. And likewiſe of ſuch Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, and Beadle as ſhall at any time be remiſſe or negligent in performance of their duties; and from time to time ſhall preſent the names of ſuch defaulters to the Lord Maior for the time being, or to ſome other of his Maieſties Iuſtices of the Peace, that puniſhment may be inflicted upon the ſaid defaulters, according to law: And that the ſaid Superviſors reſpectively (if occaſion ſhall be) ſhall proſecute, and give in evidence againſt every ſuch Delinquent where occaſion ſhall require.</p>
            <p n="5">
               <hi>5.</hi> That the Beadle ſhall in the preſence of the Conſtable and one of the Superviſors ſo to be appointed, call over the names of thoſe whoſe courſe ſhall be to watch each night reſpectively, as well at the houres appointed for their meeting in the evening, as alſo at the time appointed for the breaking up of the Watch in the morning. And that they the Beadle and Conſtables, or one of them in caſe the Superviſors be abſent, at any of the ſaid times ſhall take a note in writing of the names of ſuch of the Inhabitants then appointed to watch, as ſhall be abſent from their Watch at the houres appointed evening or morning, or any part of the night, and ſhall deliver the laid note the next day to the Superviſor, or Superviſors, that they may proſecute againſt them as afore is directed.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by Richard Cotes, Printer to the Honourable City of LONDON. <add>16. Aprill 1645.</add>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
